{"Topic": "Africa", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which country in Africa has the longest coastline?", "op1": "South Africa", "op2": "Somalia", "op3": "Ivory Coast", "op4": "Libya", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers in Africa crosses the Equator twice?", "op1": "Zambezi", "op2": "Orange", "op3": "Nile", "op4": "Congo", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which country is Africa's highest mountain Mt. Kilimanjaro located?", "op1": "Tanzania", "op2": "Kenya", "op3": "Egypt", "op4": "Ethiopia", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the most populous country in Africa?", "op1": "Egypt", "op2": "Nigeria", "op3": "South Africa", "op4": "Mozambique", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one among the following is not a landlocked country in Africa?", "op1": "Botswana", "op2": "Zambia", "op3": "Lesotho", "op4": "Nigeria", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one of the following African countries is not land-locked?", "op1": "Benin", "op2": "Chad", "op3": "Lesotho", "op4": "Mali", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following countries is not a part of Horn of Africa?", "op1": "South Africa", "op2": "Egypt", "op3": "Algeria", "op4": "Angola", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which country is the largest in area in the continent of Africa?", "op1": "1 only", "op2": "2 only", "op3": "Both 1 and 2", "op4": "Neither 1 nor 2", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Consider the following in respect of Africa:", "op1": "agricultural product", "op2": "minerals", "op3": "forest product", "op4": "fishery product", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "ch of the above is/are correct?", "op1": "West Africa", "op2": "East Africa", "op3": "North Africa", "op4": "Central Africa", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "An African country, Sudan has been broken into two recently with formation of a new country named South Sudan. Economy of South Sudan will depend on its", "op1": "Cape of Good Hope", "op2": "Cape Agulhas", "op3": "Cape Horn", "op4": "Cape Capricorn", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The TEAM-9 initiative is a techno economic cooperation venture between India and eight countries of", "op1": "Suez Canal", "op2": "Red Sea", "op3": "Mediterranean Sea", "op4": "Arabian Sea", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the southernmost tip of Africa?", "op1": "Juba", "op2": "Boma", "op3": "Nimule", "op4": "Rumbek", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following separates Africa from Europe?", "op1": "Tropic of Cancer and Equator", "op2": "Tropic of Capricorn and Equator", "op3": "Tropic of Cancer and Tropic of Capricorn", "op4": "Tropic of Cancer, Tropic of Capricorn and Equator", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the capital of newly-formed country South Sudan?", "op1": "South Africa", "op2": "Nigeria", "op3": "Egypt", "op4": "Somalia", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following geographical lines pass through Africa?"}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the largest lake in Africa?", "op1": "Lake Chad", "op2": "Lake Tanganyika", "op3": "Lake Victoria", "op4": "Lake Nakuru", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following African countries is the leading producer of gold in the world?", "op1": "South Africa", "op2": "Sudan", "op3": "Zimbabwe", "op4": "Ivory Coast", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which of the following countries is the famous Serengeti National Park located?", "op1": "South Africa", "op2": "Tanzania", "op3": "Congo", "op4": "Zambia", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Match the present names of the countries with their old names -", "op1": "1 - d; 2 - b; 3 - c; 4 - a", "op2": "1 - d; 2 - c; 3 - b; 4 - a", "op3": "1 - a; 2 - c; 3 - b; 4 - d", "op4": "1 - c; 2 - d; 3 - b; 4 - a", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following countries is completely surrounded by South Africa?", "op1": "Namibia", "op2": "Botswana", "op3": "Lesotho", "op4": "Swaziland", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following countries is also known as the Rainbow Nation?", "op1": "South Africa", "op2": "Tanzania", "op3": "Nigeria", "op4": "Zambia", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the Judicial Capital of South Africa?", "op1": "Pretoria", "op2": "Bloemfontein", "op3": "Cape Town", "op4": "Johannesburg", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "South African cricket players are called Proteas. Protea is -", "op1": "National Animal of South Africa", "op2": "National Bird of South Africa", "op3": "National Flower of South Africa", "op4": "National Language of South Africa", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Upto 70% of which of the following countries is covered by the Kalahari Desert?", "op1": "South Africa", "op2": "Botswana", "op3": "Uganda", "op4": "Nigeria", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which country is the largest producer of tea in the African continent and also the third largest producer in the world after China and India?", "op1": "Tanganyika", "op2": "Nigeria", "op3": "Kenya", "op4": "South Africa", "Answer": 4}]}